Finding Aid for Middle English Dictionary records, 1925-2008
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
- Records by Editorial Era
  - Lewis Era 1982-2001
    - Editorial Matters
      - Plan and Bibliography, 2nd ed.
        - Notes for Early History of MED for Plan, 2001-2006 (Box 17)
        - Notes for Bibliography, 2000-2006 (Box 18)
        - Final Printed Copy 2007 (Box 18)
          (with some notes on mode of reference penciled in; also includes 3 reviews from 2007-2009)
      - Q-Fascicle 1984-1985 (Box 18)
      - Reviews of MED, 1984-1992 (Box 18)
      - Supplement
        - Plans for and References to 1983-1999 (Box 18)
        - Work on and Future Projects 2000-2001 (Box 18)
      - Supplement Entries
        - Notes 1974-2008 (Box 18)
        - Articles 1917-1997 (Box 18)
    - Production Matters
      Production matters has its own category (three-fifths of box 18 and all of 19 and 20; 2.7 linear feet), divided roughly into two parts: (1) files on the use of computers and (2) style guides for the production staff. (1) Between mid-1982 and late 1983 the project explored, and experimented with, various word-processing and printing systems and, beginning in early 1984, replaced its cumbersome typewriter-generated production system with a computer-assisted system that increased the rate of publication to an average of three fascicles per year between the letter Q in 1984 and the last fascicle in 2001. (2) Between 1983 and 1999 there were so many changes and additions to the production staff that the heads of production during those years, Lidie Howes and Olivia Bottum, decided to standardize, and formalize, the rules and principles of the production process, with the result that they prepared a number of guides and notes on MED style and made them available to the staff.
      - A-Notebook Example 2000 (Box 18)
      - Back-to-Books Style Guide (Olivia Bottum's copy) 1985-2001 (Box 18)
      - B-Notebook Example (single page) 2000-2001 (Box 18)
      - Computers
        - Correspondence, Reports, etc. 1982-1984 (Box 18)
        - Correspondence, Reports, etc. 1985-1989 (Box 18)
        - Feasibility Study for Word-Processing System 1982-1983 (Box 18)
        - Planning for Computer Use 1982-1984 (Box 18)
        - Procedures for Use of Computer 1980s-1990s (Box 18)
        - Miscellaneous Notes and Instructions 1980s-1990s (Box 19)
        - Miscellaneous Examples of Problems 1980s (Box 19)
        - Printing Samples 1980s-1990s (Box 19)
        - Use of Computer for Staff (especially e-mail) 1980s-1990s (Box 19)
      - Cross-References
        - Processing and Some Examples from T 1991-2001 (Box 19)
        - Example of Sa-Sm from MTS 1988 (Box 19)
      - Draft Style Guide (by Lidie Howes) circa 1987 (Box 19)
      - Guide to the Production Process 1992-1999 (Box 19)
      - Notes on Stylistic Details (by Lidie Howes) 1983-1991, 1996-2001 (Box 19)
      - Production Staff: Miscellaneous (primarily memos) 1990-1999 (Box 19)
      - Reference/Master Copy of Stylistic Details (Box 20)
        - Styling of Definitions A-L 1980s-2001 (Box 20)
        - Styling of Definitions M-Z 1980s-2001 (Box 20)
        - Headwords, Form Sections, Etymologies 1980s-2001 (Box 20)
        - Orthography, Styling Quotations 1980s-2001 (Box 20)
        - Word Division (by Lidie Howes) 1990s (Box 20)
      - T Record Book 1991-1996 (Box 20)
      - U-Z Progress Charts (samples) 1996-2001 (Box 20)
      - W-Z Front Sheets 1998-2001 (Box 20)
- Miscellaneous MED Materials
  Records in the MISCELLANEOUS MED MATERIALS subgroup are arranged primarily by topics (reading notes, lists of MED headwords and titles, bibliographical files, transcriptions and reproductions of texts, audio-visual materials, etc.) but also chronologically wherever possible. These boxes are a variety of sizes depending on the format of the materials within them. Series include: Editorial and Bibliographical Materials, 1930s-1940s; Moore's Reading Notes; Knott's Reading Notes; Science Bibliography; Headword File; Editorial and Bibliographic Materials, 1940-2008; Middle English Texts; Audio, Digital, and Visual Material, and Artifacts; Hand-Pulled Cross References; and Quotations. The first several series (boxes 21-38) date primarily from the Moore and Knott eras.
  - Editorial and Bibliographical Materials 1930s-1940s
    The first series Editorial and Bibliographical Materials, 1930s-1940s (boxes 21-22) contains early editorial and bibliographical materials from before the project began up through the 1940s. These materials contain primarily lists of Middle English texts and names of readers from the 1930s.
    - Ewald Fl端gel Materials, pre-1930s (Box 21)
      - Material for His Chaucer Dictionary (Box 21)
      - Non-Chaucerian Material (Box 21)
    - Early List of Middle English Texts 1930s (Box 21)
    - Middle English Readers 1930s
      - Readers Assigned (Box 21)
      - Potential Readers (Box 21)
      - Unable to Read (Box 21)
      - Volunteer Help for the Future (Box 21)
    - Middle English Texts Read 1930s
      - Reading Outstanding (Box 21)
      - Texts Completed (Box 21)
      - Texts Assigned (Box 21)
      - Possible Texts to Be Read (Box 21)
    - Periodicals & Serials at University of Michigan (includes both those searched and those not searched) 1930s-1943 (Box 21)
    - Periodicals & Serials (with texts) read by Sanford Meech 1930s (Box 21)
    - Middle English Texts in Periodicals in the University Library 1930s (Box 21)
    - Medical and Botanical Texts 1930s (Box 21)
    - Scientific Vocabulary (plants, stones, mathematics, astronomy: chiefly C, D, and E words, alphabetically arranged, with notes by Katherine Fellows), late 1930s to early 1940s (Box 21)
    - Bibliography of Pictures 1930s-1940s (Box 22)
    - Special Subject Bibliography 1930s-1940s (Box 22)
  - Reading Notes and Bibliogrpahies
    The Reading Notes and Bibliogrpahies series is scomprised of files labeled Moore's Reading Notes, Knott's Notes Reading Notes and Science Bibliography.
    The series Moore's Reading Notes (boxes 23 and part of 24) contains Moore's reading notes (1930-1934). The notes are arranged alphabetically, with each letter arranged by, first, titles or authors of texts and, then, journals or series.
    Knott's Reading Notes (1935-1945) fill out the rest of box 24, made primarily in conjunction with the reading program ongoing at that time. The notes indicate which texts have glossaries, how many pages of text are included, who read them, and how many slips were taken. The series includes two sets of notes, which are, for the most part, arranged alphabetically.
    Science Bibliography (boxes 25-28) contains slips for scientific terms compiled chiefly by Margaret Ogden and Katherine Fellows, two members of the editorial staff, between the late 1930s and the late 1940s. These files contain a variety of materials, ranging from draft entries for scientific words to bibliographical files and notes, to scientific topics and categories, chiefly alchemical.
    - Moore's Reading Notes (4 1/4" x 7 1/4" cards and slips) 1930-1934 (Box 23)
      - A -- L (Box 23)
      - M -- Y (Box 24)
    - Knott's Reading Notes (4 1/4" x 7 1/4" slips) 1935-1945 (Box 24)
    - Science Bibliography (4 1/4" x 7 1/4" slips), late 1930s-late 1940s
      - Draft entries for words beginning A through S (chiefly A--C) (Ogden) (Box 25)
      - Three miscellaneous bibliographical files (Bibliography, General Bibliography, and a file arranged by topics; chiefly Ogden) (Box 25)
      - Bibliographical notes arranged in 4 categories: Ancient Classics (Box 26)
      - Medieval Classics, Middle English Texts, Modern Reference Books (Ogden) (Box 26)
      - Scientific topics (70), arranged alphabetically (chiefly Fellows) (Box 26)
      - Four categories: Apparatus and agents; Esoteric terms; Processes, operations; Substances: each category arranged generally alphabetically, with notes and glosses (almost entirely Fellows) (Box 27)
      - Bibliography and notes (Fellows) (Box 27)
      - Cut-ups from Isidore (edition by Migne) (Box 27)
      - Color plates pasted on slips with references (Fellows) (Box 27)
      - Glossarial index to Steele's Practical Chemistry (cut-ups of letter A only) (Box 27)
      - Alchemy (divided into 11 categories: notes and glosses, with some quotations attached; also some references; Fellows) (Box 28)
  - Headword File 1930s
    The Headword File (boxes 29-38) contains an alphabetical list of MED headwords, on index cards. The cards have the Middle English headwords at the top left and the OED headwords, where available, at the top right. This early attempt at a list of headwords, made in the 1930s, was superseded after 1946, when the final list began to be finalized, but remains of interest for anyone trying to reconstruct the early history of the MED.
    - a -- be (Box 29)
    - bea-cm (Box 30)
    - co -- eng (Box 31)
    - enh --gri (Box 32)
    - gro -- lat (Box 33)
    - lau -- na (Box 34)
    - ne -- que (Box 35)
    - qui -- sok (Box 36)
    - sol -- umt (Box 37)
    - un -- zy (Box 38)
  - Editorial and Bibliographical Materials 1940-2008
    The Editorial and Bibliographic Materials, 1940-2008 series (boxes 39-65) is from the Kurath, Kuhn, and Lewis eras, though they also include files that began in the Moore and Knott eras but continue into the following eras. The series consists of six sub-series: Miscellaneous Files, Bibliography Files, Title Files MED Library Files, Abbreviations for Periodicals and Serials, the Master Bibliography, and Quoting Instructions.
    The first two-fifths of box 39 contains the Miscellaneous Files sub-series from 1946 to 1954, on a variety of topics: names of readers and consultants, lists of regional texts and manuscripts, a list of manuscript abbreviations used in the Plan and Bibliography of 1954, a list of short titles not in boxes 39-43, and Kurath's distribution list for the first fascicle (E.1, published in 1952).
    The Bibliography File sub-series begins with the second three-fifths of box 39 and continues through the first quarter of box 43. It is a bibliographical file on cards: specifically, an alphabetically arranged conversion list of pre-Kurath-era titles of Middle English works, with the new short title (or "stencil" as it was called at the MED) on the same card, below. This list, which was made between the late 1940s and 1952 (before the publication of fascicle E.1), contains what the MED calls "texts" (the short titles of longer works) and "incipits" (the first few words of a short piece of verse) combined together, unlike the later printed MED bibliographies (1954, 1984, 2007), which separate the two.
    The MED Library File sub-series (box 44-46) contains a listing of the books in the former MED library as it existed in 1976, with later additions up to 2001.
    The Abbreviations for Periodicals and Serials sub-series, alphabetically arranged, and includes information on which text or texts are in each periodical or serial. This list was compiled by MED bibliographer Mary Jane Williams between 1985 and the mid- to late 1990s.
    - Miscellaneous Files
      - Middle English Readers and Consultants 1946-1950s (Box 39)
      - Regional Texts and Manuscripts 1946-1954 (Box 39)
      - Manuscript Abbreviations Used in the Plan and Bibliography, 1947-1954 (Box 39)
      - Short Titles not in the "conversion list" (Boxes 39-43) under their earlier titles or a close approximation (Box 39)
      - Distribution of Fascicle E.1 1952-1953
        - Review Copies (Box 39)
        - Presentation Copies (Box 39)
        - Committee on Dictionaries (Box 39)
        - Office Copies (Box 39)
    - Bibliography File, late 1940s-1952
      - A -- Chan (Box 39)
      - Char -- in PMLA (Box 40)
      - in Pol -- Mi (Box 41)
      - Mo -- Tra (Box 42)
      - Tre-Z (Box 43)
    - Title File, ca. late 1940s-early 1950s
      The Title File (boxes 43-44) also contain a list of titles, this time of MED texts first, and then incipits, generally alphabetical in multiple series, with a very brief description of the contents of each, made in the late 1940s or early 1950s.
      - Texts (Box 43)
      - Incipits
        - Part 1 (Box 43)
        - Part 2 (Box 44)
    - MED Library File 1976-2001
      - A -- Ed (Box 44)
      - Eg -- P (Box 45)
      - Q -- Z (Box 46)
    - Abbreviations for Periodicals and Serials 1985-1990s
      - Cards for A to Y (Box 46)
    - Master Bibliography 1947-2007
      The Master Bibliography sub-series (boxes 47-63) contain the master bibliography, alphabetically arranged. This bibliography began in 1947 and was added to, and used, until the end of the project in 2001, and even after, through 2007, when the Plan and Bibliography, 2nd edition, was published. The bibliography begins with texts (10 boxes of cards), proceeds to incipits (4 boxes), and ends with manuscripts (3 boxes).
      - Texts
        - A -- Ce (Box 47)
        - Cha -- Chu (Box 48)
        - Cl -- Ge (Box 49)
        - Gg -- Ld (Box 50)
        - Le -- Lydg (Box 51)
        - Lye -- Pr (Box 52)
        - Ps -- Ste (Box 53)
        - Stg -- WbibleProlP (Box 54)
        - WBibleProlR -- Yw (Box 55)
        - Suppl. (1984) (Box 55)
        - 2nd ed. (2007)
          - A (Box 55)
          - B --Z (Box 56)
      - Incipits
        - A -- Heyr (Box 57)
        - Hiegh -- Maysters (Box 58)
        - Men -- Thys (Box 59)
        - Timor -- Y (Box 60)
        - Suppl. (1984) (Box 60)
        - 2nd ed. (2007) (Box 60)
      - Manuscripts
        - A -- D (Box 61)
        - E -- O (Box 62)
        - P -- Y (WBible manuscripts not used because they were not collated by Forshall and Madden in their edition) (Box 63)
    - Quoting Instructions for MED Texts, 1947-2001
      Quoting Instructions (boxes 64-65) contains the quoting instructions for the MED texts listed there. These instructions were extracted from the books in the former MED library in 2010, when it was dispersed, and are filed alphabetically by stencil. If a single volume contained more than one text, then the quoting instructions for that volume are filed under the stencil of either the first text in the volume or the main text or author in the volume. Like the master bibliography, these instructions were begun in 1947 and were continued as new texts were added to the library up to 2001.
      - A -- I (Box 64)
      - J -- Z (Box 65)
  - Middle English Texts 1930s-1980s
    The Middle English Texts series(boxes 66-72) contain primarily transcriptions, facsimiles (usually photostats), and microfilms of manuscripts of Middle English texts, which were made or collected from the 1930s to the 1980s. These boxes were assembled from the materials in the former MED library when it was dispersed in 2010. The transcriptions are usually typed, though some are also handwritten; they and the facsimiles are indicated by an asterisk (*) before the short title, as is the policy in the MED Plan and Bibliography, 2nd. ed. (2007) for all unpublished sources. For the most part the microfilms are restricted to those that are not in the British Manuscripts Project (compiled by Lester K. Born; Washington, D.C., 1955), a list of microfilms housed in the University of Michigan Graduate Library. Boxes 66 to 72 also include a few handwritten variant readings from the manuscripts of Chaucer's Treatise on the Astrolabe as well as a few microfilms of both printed editions of Middle English texts and Latin texts and manuscripts.
    - Handwritten variant readings from the manuscripts of Chaucer's Treatise on the Astrolabe (Box 66)
      - Astr. by John Reidy, in 5 notebooks (Box 66)
      - Transcription of Ripley CAlch. (BodeMus) by John Reidy (Box 66)
      - Transcriptions of Nicod.(2) (Pep), Nicod.(3) (Eg), Nicod.(5) (Wor), Nicod.(4) (Hrl; typed), Nicod.(4) (Hrl; handwritten), Trev. Nicod. (Add), and Trev. Nicod. (Sal) by W.H. Hulme (Box 66)
    - Transcriptions and Facsimiles (Box 67)
      - Arabic Numerals from Cmb Ee.1.3 (Box 67)
      - Bk.Marchalsi (Dc) (Box 67)
      - Chauliac(1) (NY) (Books V to end, ff. 97b-181b, plus missing folio 10b) (Box 67)
      - Chauliac(5) (Peterh) (Box 67)
      - Diseases Women(1) (Dc), Doc. in Facs.Nat.MSS 1 (Box 67)
      - Hall Bk.I King's Lynn (Box 67)
      - Hrl.Bk.Hawking (Hrl) (Box 67)
      - Legends on Two Urine Rings from Dgb 29 (Box 67)
      - Leg.Vernicle (Hrl) (Box 67)
      - Medical Excerpts from Roy.12.G.4 Med.Miscell. (in Box 71; probably transcribed by Margaret Ogden) (Box 67)
      - Medulla (Stnh) (Box 67)
      - Plea & Mem.R.Lond.Gildh. A 77-88, PPl.A & PPl.C (Trin-C) (Box 67)
      - Recipe from Add 14252 (Box 67)
      - Recipes from Cmb Ee.1.3 (Box 67)
      - R.Gildhall King's Lynn (Box 67)
      - RJericho (Hnt) (Box 67)
      - Roy.12.G.4 Vocab. (Box 67)
      - Roy.Recipes Hawk. (Roy) (Box 67)
      - Salamon sat (Cai) (Box 67)
      - St.Brendan Conf. (Qu-O) (Box 67)
      - Terms Assoc.(2) (Cmb) (Box 67)
      - Treat.SMagus (Hrl) (Box 67)
      - Vsp.Weights (Vsp) (Box 67)
      - York MGame (Roy) (Box 67)
      - Transcriptions by W.H. Hulme of 6 items from Cmb Gg.4.32 [Ure fader in heuene, Heil marie ful of wynne, Sori is 綻e fore, Be the lef, Suo sit fairhed, I bileue in god] and of 6 items from Wor F.172 [Const.Courtenay, Narrat.Pen. Office BP, Statutes RNiger,Treat.GTempt. 12 DHumility] (Box 67)
      - Transcriptions by L.C. Sherman of 13 items chiefly from Trin-C B.14.39 (323) [Abel wes looset, A vidue, Body & S.(4), Liuisfirist, Longe slepers, MS Trin-C 323, Penaunce is, Soruhe and sey, men,Wenne 綻in eyen Wen 綻e rede, Wose wartt; along with Longe slepers (Bod 410)] (Box 67)
      - Miscellaneous [index to Lanfranc (Ashm) (Box 67)
      - Glosses from Macer (Stockh) (Box 67)
      - Summary by chapters of Trev. Barth. (Add) (Box 67)
      - Annotated xeroxes of plates XXI-XXIV from Lond. Charterhouse in Archaeol.58 (Box 67)
      - Printed text dated 1502 of the Latin Chauliac for Books VI and VII] (Box 67)
      - Book 1 (Proc.Chanc.PRO ser.C 1, file 5, 8, 9) (Box 68)
      - Books 3 and 3A (Anc.Deed (PRO), Anc.Pet. (PRO)) (Box 68)
      - Book 6 (Rolle Psalter (Bod 953), Rolle Psalter (Sid)) (Box 68)
      - Book 2 (Pet.Chanc.PRO ser.CP 1 file 12, Proc.Chanc.PRO ser.C 1 file 9, War.Chanc.PRO ser.AP 336-15860, War.Chanc.PRO ser.C 81 file 1367, 1545) (Box 69)
      - Book 13 (Abbey HG (Corp-O 155), Acc.Grantchester, Assem.Bk.A Shrewsbury, Assem.Bk1 Gild St.Geo.Norwich, Bench Bk.2 Hull, Bench Bk.3 Hull, Certificate Ipsw.CR, Church Bk.Rushall, Doc.Castle Norwich, Doc.Droitwich, Doc.Gruffi, Doc.Langney, Doc.Ludlow, Doc.Maldon, Gaude the flowre (Rwl), Gaytr.LFCatech. (Corp-O), Indent.James, Indent.Seytone, Indent.Stratford, Indent.Tylers, Indent.Wood, Invent.Gild Stratford, Let.Bishop, Let.Ormond, Let.Shrewsbury, Mirk IPP (Tan), MS Rwl.D.328, MS Rwl.Ltrg.e.3, MS Trin-O 29, Perilous Days (BodLtrg), Procl.Camb., Proph.Alphey (Cmb), Recipe Painting(2) in Archael.J.1, SMChron. (Cmb Dd), SMChron.Ctn. (Cmb Dd), Trev.Higd. (Trin-O), Will Bury, Will Shr. in Salop.SPI, Will Sud.Ipsw.PR 2, Will Suf.Ipsw.PR 1, 2) (Box 69)
      - Book 5 (Mannyng Chron.Pt.1 (Petyt), Mannyng Chron.Pt.2 (Petyt)) (Box 70)
      - Book 12 (Acc.de Weston (PRO), Chicago Photo.R.72, Choosing Mayor Norwich (Cleo), Cov.Survey Commons, December Guilt Coventry, Deed Greenwell, Exch.Misc.Deed (PRO), Excom.Dorchester (Roy), Form OBapt. (Roy), Form OMatrim. (Roy), Indent.Birm.PL, Indent.Elyngham, Let.Hen.V, Oath Bk.King's Lynn, Roy.7.A.6 Med.Recipes, Roy.12.G.4 Med.Miscell., Tit.Alphabet) (Box 70)
      - Book 14 (Indent. Redmerselle, Mun.B.Bridgewater, Plea & Mem.R.Lond.Gildh.) (Box 70)
    - Microfilms of manuscripts containing Middle English texts (Box 71)
      - All Souls College Building Accounts (Box 71)
      - Bk.Hawking (Hrl) (Box 71)
      - Cambridge Box 14 [6 manuscripts from Cambridge University Library: Dd.3.86, Mm.3.13, Kk.5.3, Hh.3.13, Kk.6.20, Mm.1.29] (Box 71)
      - Capg.St.Norb. (Hnt) (Box 71)
      - Cath.Angl. (Add) (Box 71)
      - Chauliac(1) (Chet) (Box 71)
      - Chauliac(1) (NY: negative) (Box 71)
      - Chauliac(1) (NY: positive) (Box 71)
      - Chauliac(1) (Sln 3666) (Box 71)
      - Chauliac(2) (Paris) (Box 71)
      - Chauliac(3) (Htrn) (Box 71)
      - Chauliac(4) (Cai) (Box 71)
      - Treat.Descant (Corp-C 410) [at end of a series of Latin tracts on music], Miscellaneous Manuscripts [Cutell Treat.Descant included in a series of Latin treatises on music in Bod 842 (Box 71)
      - Wallingford Exafrenon in Dgb 67], Dives & P. (Hrl 149) (Box 71)
      - Mondeville (Peterh) (Box 71)
      - Mondeville (Wel) and MS Wel.564 on one reel (Box 71)
      - Oxford Box 24 [15 manuscripts from the Bodleian Library: Bod 340, Bod 865, e Mus.63, Bod 441, Frf 3, Bod 343, BodTh 17, BodTh 18, BodTh e.16, BodLat.Lit e.10, BodTh f.10, BodHist e.49, Hatton 50, BodPoet c.3, BodPoet c.4] (Box 71)
      - Oxford Box 60 [6 manuscripts from the Bodleian Library: Bod 183, Ashm 1480, Ashm 1517, Ashm 1451, Ashm 1450, RwlPoet 10] (Box 71)
      - Sloane Manuscripts from the British Library [2 boxes: 3 on a reel in 1st: Chauliac(1) (Sln 1), Chauliac(1) (Sln 965), Chauliac(3) (Sln 3486) and Gilb.Angl. (Sln 3486); followed by a single one on a reel in 2nd: Arderne Fistula (Sln 6)] (Box 71)
      - Towneley Pl. (Hnt) (Box 71)
      - Trev. Barth. (Add: positive) (Box 71)
      - Trev. Barth. (Add: negative) (Box 71)
      - Trev. Barth. (Mrg: part 1) (Box 71)
      - Trev. Barth. (Mrg: part 2) (Box 71)
    - Microfilms of editions of Middle English texts (along with a few microfilms of Latin texts and manuscripts) (Box 72)
      - Acc.Howard in RC 57 (Box 72)
      - Albucasis Methodus Medendi (Box 72)
      - Aristotle Secretis Secretorum (Box 72)
      - Bartholomeus Anglicus (Latin) (Box 72)
      - Capgr.St. Norb. (Hnt: transcript) (Box 72)
      - Chartier Quad.(2) (StJ-C: dissertation by Richard Dwyer) (Box 72)
      - Chauliac (Latin) (Box 72)
      - Doc. in Wright Archaeol.Album (Box 72)
      - Femina (Trin-C) (Box 72)
      - Grocer Lond. (Kingdon) (Box 72)
      - Haly Abbas (Latin medical) (Box 72)
      - Henslow Recipes (Henslow) (Box 72)
      - Lelamour Macer (Sln: thesis) (Box 72)
      - Lydg. LOL (Dur-U: dissertation) (Box 72)
      - Madox Form.Angl.(1702) (Box 72)
      - Mandev.(2) (Eg) (Box 72)
      - Merlin (Cmb) Vol. 1 and Sur.Soc. 30 and 45 on one reel) (Box 72)
      - Miscellaneous Microfilms [Ripley texts in Ashmole TC (positive), Fortescue Declaration (Clermont), Halliwell Rara Mathematica, Lanfranc (Latin), Ricardus Anglicus ed. T旦ply, Wycl.37 Concl. (Tit)] (Box 72)
      - Pilgr.LM (Cmb), Pilkington Surn. (parts 1 and 2: dissertation) (Box 72)
      - Sacrist R.Ely 2 (Box 72)
      - An Edition of Some Middle English Amatory Lyric Poems (dissertation by Kenneth Wilson) (Box 72)
      - Willis Archit.Nomencl. (Box 72)
  - Audio, Digital, and Visual Materials, and Artifacts
    Audio, Digital, and Visual Material, and Artifacts (boxes 73-74) contains miscellaneous audio, digital, and visual materials, along with a few artifacts, from all editorial eras of the MED. These include: cassettes of remarks on the MED and on one of its retiring editors; a CD of an hour-long Canadian Broadcasting Co.'s radio show on the MED; floppy disks of Middle English texts; CD-ROM's of the Middle English Compendium and quotations for the supplement; photographs of MED editors and staff; slides and transparencies of medieval manuscripts; printed maps; and artifacts such as IBM typewriter balls with Middle English letters used in the early camera-ready copy. (For other photographs, see the Retirements folders in Box 16.)